(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T23:15:20.843206",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ご来場のお客様へ
To Our Visitors
2次販売グッズ (Essentials Pack)
2nd Batch Merchandise (Essentials Pack)
2次販売グッズ (Tシャツ・パーカー他)
2nd Batch Merchandise (T-shirt, Hoodie, etc.)
2次販売グッズ (キーホルダー・タペストリー他)
2nd Batch Merchandise (Keychain, Tapestry, etc.)
2次販売グッズ (ランダムコレクション)
2nd Batch Merchandise (Random Collection)
お祝いメッセージ
[Congratulatory Messages]
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention to all attendees
アニメにハマって
I got hooked on anime...
歌いたくなっちゃった！
...and really wanted to sing!
推しのシーン見ながら
Watching my favorite scenes...
カラオケ歌えるなんて
...while singing karaoke...
尊すぎてツラい！
...is so precious, it hurts!
歌いたいアニメ・ゲームソング見つけよう！
Find the anime and game songs you want to sing!
ジョイサウンド！
JOYSOUND!
全国のアミューズメント施設でゲットしてね！
Get them at amusement centers nationwide!
詳しくはキャラ広場ホロライブで検索！
For details, search "Chara Hiroba Hololive"!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon. Please wait a moment.
【Attention】演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください / 声出し応援OKです
[Attention] Please be aware of flashing lights. / Cheering loudly is OK!
【2次販売グッズ】Essentials Pack 販売中
[Concert Goods] Second round of goods now on sale: Essentials Pack
【2次販売グッズ】Tシャツ、パーカー、その他グッズ販売中
[Concert Goods] T-Shirts, Hoodies, and accessories
【2次販売グッズ】タペストリー、アクリルキーホルダー、アクリルパネル販売中
[Concert Goods] Tapestry, Acrylic Keychains, and Panels
【2次販売グッズ】ランダム REBOOT コレクション販売中
[Concert Goods] Random REBOOT Collections
Get up and fight!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: To All Attendees
2次販売グッズ
Second-Round Merchandise
本日は、星街すいせいライブ『SuperNova:REBOOT』にご来場いただき、ありがとうございます。
Thank you for coming to Hoshimachi Suisei Live "SuperNova:REBOOT" today.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
To ensure you enjoy the concert to the end, I have a few announcements.
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は、固くお断りいたします。
Photography, recording, and the use of recording equipment during the performance are strictly prohibited.
館内は禁煙となっております。喫煙はご遠慮ください。
The venue is non-smoking. Please refrain from smoking.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、無理をせず、近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
Should you feel unwell, please do not push yourself and notify a nearby staff member.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、大きく飛び跳ねる、ステージに物を投げ込むなど、他のお客様のご迷惑になったり公演を妨げる行為は、一切禁止です。
Actions that disrupt the performance or cause trouble for others, such as moshing, diving, jumping excessively, or throwing objects onto the stage, are strictly prohibited.
ルールを守って盛り上がってください。みんな今日持ってきてくれてるうちわもね、高く掲げすぎないように気をつけてくださいね。
Please follow the rules and have fun. Also, please be careful not to raise your fans too high today.
ありがとう、後ろの人見えなくなっちゃうからね。
Thank you, as it might block the view of those behind you.
また、本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席が映り込む場合がございます。
Additionally, there are cameras inside the venue for video broadcasting and photography, and the audience seats may be captured.
映像や写真はプロモーション等に使用される可能性がございますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
Please be aware in advance that these videos and photos may be used for promotional purposes.
はーい！
Okay!
また、ライブのハッシュタグは、「#駆け巡る星街っせい」です！
Also, the hashtag for the concert is "#KakemeguruHoshimachissei"!
ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてください。
Please use the hashtag to build up the excitement.
いっぱい見たいよタグ、ありがとね、いっぱい投稿してくれて。
I want to see lots of tags! Thank you for posting so much.
それでは、開演までもう少しです！
Well then, it's just a little longer until the show starts!
みんなで一緒に盛り上がりましょう！星街すいせいでした！
Let's all get excited together! This was Hoshimachi Suisei!
REBOOT
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
革命の、その先へ。
To the other side of the revolution.
SUPERNOVA REBOOT
(bibbidi-bobbidi-boo-wa... / bibbidi-bobbidi-boo-wa...)
ケーアリーナ！
K-Arena!
盛り上がる準備できてますか？
Are you ready to get hyped?
さてすいちゃんはここだよ！
Now, Sui-chan is right here!
見えてますか？ここですよ！
Can you see me? I'm right here!
うう、見つけて見つけて、すいちゃんここだよ！
Ooh, find me, find me! Sui-chan is right here!
お、みんなのことよく見える！
Oh, I can see everyone so well!
みんな、こっちこっち！
Everyone, over here, over here!
みんなの持ってるペンライトを見せてください！
Please show me the penlights you're holding!
いいね、みんなの顔よく見えるよ！
Nice! I can see everyone's faces clearly!
ぬいぐるみもたくさんありがとう！
Thank you so much for all the plushies too!
つまんないデイズ 散々ね
Boring days, already over!
奇跡願ってるだけの人生
A life where you’re just wishing for miracles
watch me do...
didut-didut-didut-didut トリック無しのマジック
didut-didut-didut-didut, magic with no tricks
Wanna be free! だってまだふりだし
Wanna be free! Because I'm still at the starting line
hey タクシー ちょっと宇宙迄
Hey taxi, take me to space for a bit
秒針は音を立てて 夜を急かす 魔物のように
The second hand ticks loudly, like a monster urging the night.
人生は 一瞬にして
Life is, in an instant,
溶ける魔法 それならば駆け抜けて想い通り！
magic that melts. If so, run through it as you wish!
おしゃまな馬車 飛び乗って drivin'
Jump on the playful carriage and start drivin'
あたしは大変身 メイクアップ！
I'm in the middle of a great transformation, make-up!
我儘に 燦きに注意
Be careful not to get caught up in selfishness
洒落た街で dancin'
Dancing in a stylish city
ありがとう！
Thank you!
皆々 御唱和あれ！
Everyone, sing along!
こんがらがっても仕様が無いから シューズと繋いで
Even if it's chaotic, there's no other way, connect the shoes
今夜に明日など無い ならば自由に踊ったもん勝ちでしょう？
There's no tomorrow tonight, so those who dance freely win, right?
うわー！見えるよー！
Wow! I can see you!
dance! ラリラリホ どんな問題も解は一つ
Dance! La la la li ho, every problem has only one solution
白紙も正解も間違いも愛す 本当のあたしの理想
Love blank papers, correct answers, and mistakes, my true ideal
なんだか世界は限界の気配がして
The world seems to have limits I can feel
ただただ安心じゃあ心配
Just being safe is worrying
今すぐ jumpin' jumpin' out
Jumpin' out right now
chitty chitty bang bang
chitty bang bang
唯々諾々に 危機感 抱く 日々に
In days when I feel an urgent crisis
ぎりぎり 爆発 気味
Explosive feelings are at their limit
たった今 発散 して しまおう か
Should I let it all out now?
まだまだ ビィビィ弾 巧妙に乱射
Still firing away skillfully
一発じゃあ撃ち足りないわ
One shot is not enough
ついに 導き出した 君にアンサー
Finally, I found the answer for you
灰に成る迄踊って居よう
Let's dance until we turn to ash
いくよー！
Here we go!
最高！
Awesome!
見えてるよ、見えてるよー！
I can see you, I can see you!
おしゃまな馬車 飛び乗って drivin'
Jump on the playful carriage and start drivin'
あたしは大変身 メイクアップ！
I'm in the middle of a great transformation, make-up!
我儘に 燦きに注意
Be careful not to get caught up in selfishness
洒落た街で dancin'
Dancing in a stylish city
左様なら グッバイ劣等感
Goodbye, inferiority complex
何時かは 喝采 クラップ オウ デエンス
Someday, applause, clap, audience
皆々 御唱和あれ！
Everyone, sing along!
こんがらがっても仕様が無いから シューズと繋いで
Even if it's chaotic, there's no other way, connect the shoes
今夜に明日など無い ならば自由に踊ったもん勝ちでしょう？
There's no tomorrow tonight, so those who dance freely win, right?
遠くて近くて傍にいるのに
You're far yet close, right beside me
僕はどれくらい知れているんだろう
Yet how much do I truly know you?
眺める空 見つめるときに 焦がれてる姿が浮かび上がる
When I gaze at the sky, your longed-for figure appears
消えないでよ
Please don't fade away
願うたび 輝いて
Shining brighter every time I wish
運命なのか 幻なのか
Is it destiny, or is it an illusion?
あぁ
Ah...
旋律が心に咲く
A melody blooms in my heart
すべての歪みを吐き捨てていい
I can spit out all of the distortion
自由をあなたと抱きしめたい
I want to embrace freedom with you
同じ夢の中
Inside the exact same dream
目覚めをたどるなら
If I trace our awakening
掴んだ不安を眠らせに
To put the anxieties I gripped to sleep
ここには僕らしかいられない
No one but us can be here
覗いた窓の外には帳
Outside the window I peeked through is a veil
秘めた声 静かに響き渡ってゆく
My hidden voice quietly echoes through the night
あなたの朝へと帰りたい
I want to return to your morning
この声は届いてる？
Is this voice reaching you?
心はここにある
My heart is right here
どんな未来繋がっていくんだろう
I wonder what kind of future we're connecting to
眩しい君のサイン
Your dazzling sign
滲む向こう側
Is blurred on the other side
いつまでそこに立ってるんだろう
I wonder how long you'll stand there
祈るたび 包まれて
Wrapped up every time I pray
愛憐なのか 施しなのか
Is it pity, or is it charity?
あぁ
Ah...
旋律が心に咲く
A melody blooms in my heart
誰にも言えずに見つめるだけ
Unable to tell anyone, only staring
すべての歪みを吐き捨てていい
I can spit out all of the distortion
自由をあなたと抱きしめたい
I want to embrace freedom with you
同じ夢の中 目覚めをたどるなら
Inside the exact same dream, if I trace our awakening
サボタージュ はにかんでいく
Sabotage, smiling shyly,
パッパッパラッパパパラパ
Pappapparappa papaparapa,
渋々おねむに
reluctantly going to sleep.
ここには僕らしさの「こ」の字もない
There isn't even a trace of who I am here.
覗いた窓のストーリーはトバリ
The story through the peeked window is a veil,
決めた言葉 雫に 響き渡ってく
the decided words echo through the droplets.
あなたの場所へと届けていたい
I want them to reach where you are.
集まってくれた皆さん、もっともっと聴かせてください！
Everyone who gathered here, let me hear you more and more!
冷え切った太陽に 向かわされてずっと
Forced to face the freezing sun all this time,
縛り付けられている 星の上
I've been bound onto this planet.
逆らったメッセージが 流れ出して 落ちて
A rebellious message starts flowing and falls down,
濁った街の底 歌っていく
singing from the bottom of this muddy city.
きっと誰も
Surely everyone,
ただ 一人で
is all alone,
口を噤みながら 耐えながら 泣いているんだ
holding their breath, enduring, and weeping.
忘れない「愛してる」「大嫌い」「大好き」
I won't forget: "I love you," "I hate you," "I adore you."
ただ重い、辛いの？ 想いが褪せる？
Is it just heavy and painful? Are my feelings fading?
今日も擬態して 咲いていく この感情が
Imitating others today as well, this blooming emotion...
音の中で 初めて光り合うんだね
...for the very first time, they light each other up in the sound.
歌の中で 初めて響き出すんだね
For the very first time, they start echoing in the song.
冷え切った体温と 並んだ表情に
With freezing body temperatures and aligned expressions,
臆病になっていた 街の上
I had grown cowardly above this city.
叶わない暴力と 史上まれな重力に
To an ungrantable violence and unprecedented gravity,
名前も苛立ちも 植え付けられている
our names and frustrations are implanted.
なんて どこかで 吐いた言い訳が
Such excuses spat out somewhere,
声を奪ったまま 呪いみたいになっているんだ 今更
have stolen my voice, becoming like a curse at this late stage.
割れない「解ってよ」「信じて」「嘘つき」
Unbreakable: "Understand me," "Believe me," "Liar."
嫌になるくらいに 想いうずまく
To a disgusting degree, my feelings swirl around.
今日も振り回されていく もがく明日が
Today, once again, I'm getting dragged around as the struggling tomorrow...
飛び上がる準備をしてる
...is preparing to leap up.
何もかも反発して
Everything is repelling,
崩壊して 沈んでいく
collapsing, and sinking down.
もっともっと！
More, more!
いつだって 信じたい そうだよ そうだよ
I want to believe, always, yes I do, yes I do.
嫌いじゃない 好きじゃない
It's not that I hate it, it's not that I love it,
全部が一つだ
it's all just one.
会いたい 足りない
I want to meet, it's not enough,
どうしたい どうしよう
what do I want to do, what should I do?
交わせない 聞かせて
We can't cross paths, let me hear you,
聞かせて
let me hear you.
伝えたい
I want to convey...
「愛してる」「大嫌い」「大好き」
..."I love you," "I hate you," "I adore you."
ただ重い、辛いの？ 想いの果てまで
Is it just heavy and painful? To the very end of my thoughts,
今日もまた 叫んでる この感情が
today, once again, this blooming emotion is screaming...
音の中で 初めて光り合うまで
...until we finally light each other up in the sound,
あなたのその胸で 響き出すまで
...until it starts echoing inside your chest!
「愛してる」
"I love you,"
「大嫌い」
"I hate you,"
嘘だよ
I'm lying,
「大大好き」
"I adore you!"
ありがとうー！
Thank you so much!
盛り上がってますね！
We're really heating up here!
ということで星街すいせいライブ、「Supernova Revolt」いよいよ始まりました！
And with that, Hoshimachi Suisei's live concert, "Supernova Revolt," has finally begun!
皆さん、びっくりしたんじゃないですか？冒頭ね。
Everyone, weren't you surprised? By the opening, I mean.
ねえ
Hey.
一瞬どこにいるか分かんなかったんじゃないかな？
For a moment, did you lose track of where I was?
分かんなかったね
You didn't know, did you?
あれ？出てこない、出てこないじゃん？あれ？って思ったかな？
Did you think, "Huh? She's not coming out?"
端っこのね、あの、あそこらへんの人はね
The people sitting near the edges over there...
うおおお！ってなったことと思いますけれども
...must have gone, "Whoa!" I bet.
さあ
Now then...
ありがとう
Thank you!
まずは自己紹介からね、いきたいと思いますよ
First of all, I'd like to start with my self-introduction!
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石！バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！
The rough gem of a star who appeared like a comet! Virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei here!
すいちゃんはー？
Sui-chan is...?
今日もかわいい！
...cute today too!
元気だね君たち、今日も
You guys are so energetic, today too!
いやあ
Wow...
でもさ、まだいけるんじゃない？
But you know, you can do even better, right?
じゃあいくよ！すいちゃんはー？
Alright, here we go! Sui-chan is...?
できるやないかい！
Look at that, you can do it!
さてさて、今回のライブはですね
Well, well, about today's live concert...
去年行いました武道館公演の再現として
It's a recreation of the Budokan show we held last year...
セトリとかがね、結構あの、似てるんですけど
So the setlist is quite similar, but...
2曲目がもうすでにね、前回と違いましたね保存
The second song was already different from last time!
ね？
Right?
お、じゃあ結構なんか変わってたりするのかな？
Oh, so maybe quite a few things have changed?
とか言って、全然変わってなかったり
Or maybe I say that and nothing has changed at all...
まあただ、一つ言えるのは
Well, but one thing I can say is...
このKアリーナという会場で、やりたかった演出とか
The kind of staging I wanted to do at this K-Arena...
もうレーザーバチバチとかもう演出がもう、もりもりになってるんで
...like crazy lasers and tons of amazing effects...
めちゃめちゃアップグレードしてるんで
...have been upgraded so much!
で、私自身も
And I, myself...
たくさん練習してきましたんで
...have practiced a whole lot...
ダンスとかね、ちょっと頑張ってきたんで
...and worked hard on things like dancing!
そういう、去年からパワーアップした姿をお見せできればなと思って
So I hope I can show you how much I've powered up...
はい、このライブとなっております
...and that's what this live concert is all about.
さて、今回もですね、えー、いつもの通り
Now, today as well, just like always...
バンドさん引き連れております！バンドさーん！
I have the band with me! Band guys!
そしてそして
And also, also...
ちょいリハのね、動画とかをショートで投稿させてもらってるんですけど
I've been posting rehearsal videos on Shorts...
気づいた人いるよね？
...and some of you noticed, right?
今回はストリングスさんがいらっしゃいます！ストリングスさーん！
This time, we have a strings section! Strings guys!
いやもう、かっこいいんだからストリングスさん入るだけでね
Wow, it's just so cool just having strings added.
ストリングスって何かって知ってる？
Do you know what strings are?
あれだよ、あの、バイオリン、ふぉ、わ、わ、わ、わってやつ
It's those... you know, the violins that go "🎻 whee-ooo-whee-ooo."
もう今日しか聞けないライブアレンジをね、バンドさんがたくさん
The band made so many live arrangements that you can only hear today...
たくさん作ってくださいましたので
...so many of them for us!
もうしょっぱなからビビデバのね、ストリングス入ったバージョンがかっこよすぎて
Right from the start, the strings version of Bibbidiba was so cool...
アゲアゲになっちゃいましたね
...it got me totally hyped up!
めちゃめちゃよかったー！
It was so incredibly good!
さあ、そしてそして
Now, and also...
残念ながらここに、来られなかった星詠みたちがいます
Unfortunately, there are Hoshiyomis who couldn't be here in person.
ここに
Right here...
ここに、来られなかった星詠みたち
...to all the Hoshiyomis who couldn't make it here...
画面の向こうの君たち
...to you guys on the other side of the screen...
「見たかったよー」って言ってるやつ、お前聞き取るじゃないか
...to those saying, "I wanted to see it so bad!" I can hear you!
ちょっとね、なんかここらへんになんか、あれ、なんか
You see, around here, I can see...
「ここにいるぞ」お、なんか見える
..."I'm right here!" Oh, I can see it.
「見てるよ」おお
"I'm watching!" Oh.
「イェーイ、俺はここにいるぞ」
"Yay, I am right here!"
「行きたかった」「吊るされてます」
"I wanted to go," "I'm being suspended,"
「号泣」
..."crying my eyes out."
悲しいな、「ニューヨークからこんにちは」あ、ニューヨークからこんにちは！
How sad. "Hello from New York!" Ah, hello from New York!
おおー
Oh!
え、気になるよ
Wow, I'm curious.
海外星詠みの皆さん！
All the overseas Hoshiyomis!
す、すごい
Th-That's amazing!
え、海外星詠みではない皆さん！
All of you who are not overseas Hoshiyomis!
素晴らしい！もうどっちも素晴らしいですね
Wonderful! Well, both are wonderful!
はい、ということで、配信の方もですね、たくさんファンサしますので
Yes, so I will give lots of fanservice to the stream viewers too!
寂しくさせませんからね！絶対に最初から最後まで全部見てくださいね！はい、バチコーン！
I won't let you feel lonely! Make sure to watch everything from start to finish! Bam, wink!
ではでは、ライブの感想は、ハッシュタグ「駆け巡る星街
Now then, post your thoughts on the live show with the hashtag #KakemeguruHoshimachi...
サイ」でたくさんポストしてください！ポスト？
...SUI! Please post a lot! "Post"?
「ツイート」だよね！？
It's "tweet," right?!
ツイートだよな！まったく、台本はいつまでも「ポスト」って書いてあるんだから。おかしいな。
It's tweet! Geez, the script always writes "post" for some reason. How strange.
さて、YouTube、TikTokでご覧の
Now, for those watching on YouTube and TikTok...
ただで見ているあなたたち
For those of you watching for free...
3曲までよ、ただで見れるのは
You can only watch up to three songs for free!
えー？
Eh?!
ありがとう、代わりにね、言ってくれて。ありがとう
Thanks for saying that for me. Thank you.
さあ、まだまだ一緒に盛り上がりたいみんなは
Now, for everyone who wants to keep having fun together...
概要欄から、下なのかな？上なのかな？下かな？
...head to the description! Is it below? Or above? Below?
概要欄から配信サイトへレッツゴー！
From the description, head to the streaming site! Let's go!
いいですか皆さん？盛り上がる準備できてますか？次行っちゃっていいんですか？
Are you ready, everyone? Are you ready to get hyped? Can we move on to the next song?!
リブートしたスーパーノヴァ、全身で浴びてください！
Bask in the rebooted Supernova with your whole body!
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
[On-Screen Text: The free viewing part has ended. Thank you for watching!]
SUPERNOVA 2026.2.21 (土) K-Arena Yokohama
[On-Screen Text: SUPERNOVA | Saturday, February 21, 2026 | K-Arena Yokohama]
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching!